Vipin Chaudhary

Delhi, India

vipin14119@iiitd.ac.in

linkedin.com/in/volt-vipin

Summary

Experienced Data Scientist with a demonstrated history of working in the AI industry. Strong engineering professional skilled in Computer Science, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Pytorch, Apache Spark, Hive, Python, JAVA,

Graduated from IIIT Delhi as Computer Scientist engineer. Along the way I did quite a few internships in variety of domain including Full Stack, Android/IOS dev then finally settled on Artificial Intelligence as my domain of utmost interest. Currently working in Airtel as ML/AI engineer.

I have build and been a part of many interesting projects -

- # User Home and Office location prediction from usage pattern and behaviour analysis
- # Research Paper on LipSync project using GAN and GRUs
- # Sports Match Video summarisation using GAN and LSTMs
- # Daily Top News from Twitter analysis using NLP
- # Question Recommender system for students for E-Learning platforms
- # Automatic Terrain generation from 2D Lines using GAN
- # and many more...

Experience



Airtel Digital

Jan 2019 - Present (3 years 11 months +)

Machine Learning Intern

Aptence

Jul 2017 - Dec 2017 (6 months)

Questions and Challenges recommender system for students according to their past performance and behaviours with coldStart and hotStart tackled.



docment.ai (formerly Hypothizer)

Dec 2016 - Oct 2017 (11 months)

Building server and API for making cars fully automated assistance , using computer vision and deep learning technology

Full-stack Developer

Learnix Edutech

May 2016 - Oct 2017 (1 year 6 months)

Developed an e-learning platform for students using django python, javascript, angularjs and bootstrap

Application Developer

Aptence

Dec 2016 - Jul 2017 (8 months)

Hybrid application for IOS/Android in React-Native with Django as backend. Students can take challenges and compete with students globally and watch themselves grow.

Student Internship

HT Media Ltd

Dec 2016 - Jun 2017 (7 months)

Developed an online platform using PHP to create and post advertisements in India's leading newspapers PAN India

Lead Programmer

Greenesto Design Studio

May 2016 - Sep 2016 (5 months)

Developed E-commerce cum information platform for Solar energy related products and blogging capabilities for social awareness about solar energy with templating system for blogging.

Web Developer

Archimedis Healthcare

May 2015 - Jul 2015 (3 months)

Developed web modules for company ERP system, using python based framework Odoo

Education

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology, Delhi

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2014 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications



Neural Networks and Deep Learning - Coursera

DMQ44DQLYY3F

Skills

Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Machine Learning • Deep Learning • Computer Vision • Data Mining • Data Structures • Algorithms • Android App Development • Computer Science • Software Development